Guide to the Jerome Long Collection of World War II African American Court Martial Records, 1944 - 2000
Jerome Long Collection of World War II African American Court Martial Records1944 - 2000
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Jerome Long
2015-21
1.5
4
Jerome H. Long served as an Associate Professor of Religion at Wesleyan University from 1971 to 1997. Born in 1931 in Little Rock, Arkansas, he earned a doctorate in the History of Religions from the University of Chicago Divinity School in 1973, and completed his doctoral dissertation on the Mbuti Pygmies of Zaire and the Bushmen of southern Africa. While at Wesleyan, he helped found the Center for African American Studies (CAAS) and acted as its director from 1979 to 1982. His research focuses on African and African American myth, religion, and ritual, and on the experiences of African American soldiers stationed in Europe in World War II.
The collection involves research on African American soldiers who were court martialed, found guilty, and executed while they served in the U.S. Army in World War II. Sources include court martial documents, such as transcripts and testimonies, in addition to Long's personal research materials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Gift of Jerome H. Long.
Biographical Note
Jerome H. Long served as an Associate Professor of Religion at Wesleyan University from 1971 to 1997. Born in 1931 in Little Rock, Arkansas, he earned a doctorate in the History of Religions from the University of Chicago Divinity School in 1973, and completed his doctoral dissertation on the Mbuti Pygmies of Zaire and the Bushmen of southern Africa. While at Wesleyan, he helped found the Center for African American Studies (CAAS) and acted as its director from 1979 to 1982. His research focuses on African and African American myth, religion, and ritual, and on the experiences of African American soldiers stationed in Europe in World War II.
Collection Overview
The collection involves research on African American soldiers who were court martialed, found guilty and executed while they served in World War II. Sources include court martial documents, such as transcripts and testimonies, in addition to Long's personal research materials.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is organized alphabetically by last name of the soldier(s) implicated in the court martial. Multiple folders related to the same court martial are arranged chronologically.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Long, Jerome H., 1931- .; World War, 1939-1945--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--African Americans.; Courts-martial and courts of inquiry.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I. Records
  - Research materials,1988 Nov 25 - 1999 Oct 5 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Research materials,2000 Apr 28 - 2000 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agee, Amos; Smith, John; and Watson, Frank, 1944 Sept 3 - 1944 Oct 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agee, Amos; Smith, John; and Watson, Frank, 1944 Oct 18 - 1945 Feb 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agee, Amos; Smith, John; and Watson, Frank, 1945 Feb 17 - 1945 Dec 7 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agnew, James; Burns, Ernest; Crawford, Willie; Fleming, Hildrith; Lawton, Herbert; Lilly, John; Lockett, John; Moultrie, Herbert; Oree, Percy; and Washington, Willie, 1944 Oct 5 - 1944 Oct 29 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agnew, James; Burns, Ernest; Crawford, Willie; Fleming, Hildrith; Lawton, Herbert; Lilly, John; Lockett, John; Moultrie, Herbert; Oree, Percy; and Washington, Willie, 1944 Nov 9 - 1944 Dec 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agnew, James; Burns, Ernest; Crawford, Willie; Fleming, Hildrith; Lawton, Herbert; Lilly, John; Lockett, John; Moultrie, Herbert; Oree, Percy; and Washington, Willie, 1944 Dec 8 - 1979 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hendricks, James, 1944 Aug 16 - 1944 Sept 7 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hendricks, James, 1944 Sept 7 - 1944 Dec 22 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Henry, Leroy, 1944 May 6 - 1944 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Henry, Leroy, 1944 June 17 - 1944 Sept 20 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Jefferies, Charles, 1944 Dec 22 - 1945 July 17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Jones, Cubia and Pearson, Robert, 1944 Dec 4 - 1944 Dec 16 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Jones, Cubia and Pearson, Robert, 1944 Dec 16 - 1945 Apr 3 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Jones, John and Nelson, Henry, 1945 Jan 29 - 1945 Mar 29 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Jones, John and Nelson, Henry, 1945 Mar 30 - 1945 July 27 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mack, William, 1944 Sept 8 - 1987 Apr 23 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McMurray, Fred and Till, Louis, 1944 June 30 - 1944 Dec 22 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - McMurray, Fred and Till, Louis, 1945 Jan 4 - 1945 Feb 17 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - McMurray, Fred and Till, Louis, 1945 Feb 17 - 1955 Oct 17 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Perry, Herman, 1944 Mar 5 - 1944 Aug 7 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Perry, Herman, 1944 Aug 7 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Perry, Herman, 1944 Aug 8 - 1945 Apr 12 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Wimberly, Willie Jr., 1944 Aug 9 - 1944 Aug 17 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Wimberly, Willie Jr., 1944 Aug 17 - 2000 Apr 18 (Box 4, Folder 2)